Downloaded from||YTS.MX
Here! Over here!
And there was a time
when the world was so young,
there had not yet been a sunrise.
But even then there was light.
Well, is it finished yet?
Even you couldn't possibly believe
that old scrap will float.
It's not going to float.
It's going to sail.
-Stop!
No, don't!
-Stop, you'll break it!
Stop! Don't!
-Come on.
-Stop, you're breaking it! Stop!
I told you it wouldn't float.
Get off me!
Lose your footing again, Galadriel?
It was a good ship, sister.
I made it just as you taught me.
Do you know why a ship floats
and a stone cannot?
Because the stone sees only downward.
The darkness of the water is vast
and irresistible.
The ship feels the darkness as well,
striving moment by moment
to master her and pull her under.
But the ship has a secret.
For unlike the stone,
her gaze is not downward but up.
Fixed upon the light that guides her,
whispering of grander things
than darkness ever knew.
But sometimes the lights shine
just as brightly
reflected in the water
as they do in the sky.
It's hard to say which way is up
and which way is down.
How am I to know which lights to follow?
But that seems so simple.
The most important truths often are.
But you must learn
to discern them for yourself.
I won't always be here
to speak them to you.
You won't?
Come along. Mother and Father are waiting.
We had no word for death.
For we thought our joys would be unending.
We thought our light would never dim.
So when the Great Foe, Morgoth,
destroyed the very light of our home...
We resisted.
And a legion of Elves went to war.
We left Valinor, our home,
and journeyed to a distant realm.
One filled with untold perils
and strange creatures beyond count.
A place known as Middle-earth.
Valaron kalanen!
Firuvantë!
They said it would be over quickly,
but the war left Middle-earth in ruin.
And would last centuries.
Now, we learned many words for death.
In the end, Morgoth would be defeated.
But not before much sorrow.
For his Orcs had spread
to every corner of Middle-earth,
Multiplying ever greater
under the command
of his most devoted servant,
a cruel and cunning sorcerer.
They called him Sauron.
My brother vowed to seek him out
and destroy him.
But Sauron found him first
and marked his flesh with a symbol.
One whose meaning even our wisest
could not discern.
And there, in the darkness,
his vow became mine.
And so, we hunted.
To the ends of the Earth we hunted Sauron.
But the trail grew thin.
Year gave way to year.
Century gave way to century.
And for many Elves, the pain of those days
passed out of thought and mind.
More and more of our kind
began to believe that Sauron
was but a memory.
And the threat, at last, was ended.
I wish I could be one of them.
Commander Galadriel.
This company has followed you
to the very edge of the world.
But none who ever dared search
for this last stronghold
has ever found anything.
It's been years
since the last Orc was sighted.
Is it not possible the other commanders
are right and our enemy is no more?
Night is closing in.
How long can living flesh endure
where even sunlight fears to tread?
Perhaps we would be wise to camp here.
And tomorrow, begin the journey home.
We are losing the light.
Commander, wait!
No. We keep moving.
Galadriel, stop!
There's nothing out here.
We should have been there by now.
We are there.
This is it.
This is where the Orcs gathered
after Morgoth's defeat.
Far more must have escaped,
than we ever imagined.
My hand is past feeling.
No.
This place is so evil,
our torches give off no warmth.
This way.
How can you be certain?
It's colder than the rest.
A door was filled in here.
Bring it down.
What devilry is this?
These Orcs were meddling
with the powers of the Unseen World.
Some dark sorcery of old.
But what was their purpose?
Surely, it is lost to the ages now.
Whatever happened here was long ago.
Water.
Even stone cannot hide the mark
of one whose very hand
is flame unquenched.
He was here.
Sauron was here.
Tell the others to rest while they can.
At sunrise we move on.
We'll take the search further north.
Further north?
This mark was left as a trail
for Orcs to follow.
The last time I saw it was on my brother.
We must follow it.
The mark is centuries old.
Whoever left it could be long dead.
Or lying in wait, gathering strength,
perfecting whatever dark art
eluded him here.
We exceeded our orders months ago.
Surely we must first return home
to take counsel with the High King.
I promise you there is not a soul
amongst our company
who yearns for home more than I.
I can still feel the light of the Trees
on my face.
I can still see it.
And until we are certain
every trace of our enemy is vanquished...
I can never return.
Snow-troll!
We should never
have come in here.
We leave soon enough.
The order is given.
We march at first light.
Then you shall do so alone.
Something's wrong here.
Nothing to hunt.
Wolves in every thicket.
Don't you think
it's the least bit strange?
World's strange.
If I let 'em pitch-kettle me,
I'd never get off me barstool.
-Oi, oi!
Keep walkin'.
Why?
Looked like a badger. Maybe a fox.
More likely a Harfoot.
A Harfoot?
Ugh. Don't care to be seein' none,
but if you do, watch yourself.
Dangerous creatures they are.
You're making it up.
Come on. Rattle your dags!
Let's just get to the lake before sundown.
-Huh? Huh.
Clear and clear.
Nori!
Travelers? At this time of year?
-It's an omen, I warrant ya.
-Mmm-hmm. Bad one. As bad as they come.
-Easy, Malva.
The last time we had travelers this early,
it was the Great Frost.
And there's no misremembering
how bleak a season that was.
More than likely they just got lost,
that's it.
Has to be the reason.
You're gonna spoil dinner.
I've looked high and low again.
The wee ones are still out there.
They'll be fine, Goldie.
Nori's with them. You know Nori.